fastrawviewer.com 2019-10-14

# Privacy Policy | FastRawViewer

This data protection declaration is intended to inform the users of this website about the type, scope, and purpose of the collection and use of personal data by the website operator LibRaw LLC _(hereinafter referred to as website operator)_.

The website operator takes your data protection very seriously and treats your personal data confidentially and in accordance with legal regulations.

The website operator intends to give you as much control as reasonably possible over your personal data. In general, you can visit this website without revealing any of personal data that can be used to identify you, such as your name, email address, telephone numbers, postal address, credit card information, occupation, company name, industry, product application, contact preferences, or experience with products offered on this website.

There are times, however, when the website operator may need information from you in order to provide the services you've requested. If you wish to order products or information from the website operator through this website, including registering for various services that may be available, you may be required to share certain personal data with the website operator so that the website operator can process your order or request. The website operator also may use this personal data to notify you about special promotions for or new major releases of the website operator's products.

The website operator will not otherwise use, share, disseminate, publish, or disclose your personal data _(except as may reasonably be required in response to litigation, investigations, or other legally required disclosures)_.

Please keep in mind that any data transmission over the Internet can be subject to security vulnerabilities. The website operator is not responsible for the security of any information you transmit to the website operator through third party services. Once your information has been received by the website operator, the website operator will make the best effort to ensure the safety and security of this information on the website operator's systems.

## Collection of Personal Information

### Product Download

You do not need to provide ANY personal information to download any product offered on this website.

The website operator collects only an IP address used for download and solely for statistical evaluations.

### Order Placement and Purchased Product Activation

For online order placement with this website, you will be transferred to the website operator's third-party e-commerce partner _(such as MyCommerce Digital River Company)_ for billing. You can access their privacy statement online _(<https://www.mycommerce.com/corporate-policy/>)_.

The website operator receives only your registration name, e-mail, product title, and a transaction identifier, as well as your address and phone number as you choose to provide them in the order form. This information, provided by you during the order placement, is used to generate a unique license key, which is the only thing you need for the registration and activation of the purchased product.

The website operator does not receive your credit card information. All payment details _(such as credit card number, expiration date, etc...)_ stay with the website operator's billing partner and are never transmitted to the website operator.

### Forum Participation

No registration is required for forum participation. The website operator will answer your question in any case.

If you choose to register, any forum registration personal information used to determine your person that can be traced back to you will include only your registration name _(username)_ and email address.

You can unsubscribe at any time using the following procedure:

  * Click this link or copy and paste it to your browser: <https://www.fastrawviewer.com/user/>
  * Select Edit tab
  * Click Cancel account button at page bottom
  * You will receive the confirmation email with the link. You can cancel your account on this website's forum by clicking this link or copying and pasting it into your browser.

### Contact Form

If you want to contact the website operator through the contact form, the only contact data required from you that can be used to determine your person and that can be traced back to you, is the contact name and email address.

## Handling of Personal Data

The website operator only uses and passes on your personal data if this is permitted by law.

Personal data is all information that serves to determine your person and that can be traced back to you.

  * Website operator may use personal data _(namely, registration name, email, address, phone number, if provided, and a transaction identifier)_ that was collected by the website operator's e-commerce partner during online order placement and passed to the website operator to:
  * Fulfill our contractual obligations.
  * Determine registered users' eligibility for discounts on major software releases.
  * Restore a user's license key number if such is requested by the user.
  * On rare occasions, provide user with notifications related to products that you have licensed from the website operator.
  * Improve the quality of this website and the products mentioned on it.

The website operator never shares, sells, rents, or leases email addresses or any other personal data to any third parties.

## Handling of Contact Data

If you contact the website operator through the contact options offered or in any other form as well as if you choose to register for the forum participation, your details will be stored so that they can be used to process and respond to your inquiry. This data will not be passed on to third parties without your consent.

## Collecting and Handling of Access Data

### Web Site Server Log Files

Like with most standard websites, the website operator uses log files to automatically log information such as IP addresses, browser type, internet service provider _(“ISP”)_ , referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp, and number of clicks.

The data collected is used solely for statistical evaluations and to improve the website, that is to manage traffic loads, identify the content most commonly accessed and determine information technology requirements for providing reliable service, or other web management, deployment, tracking, maintenance and similar activities. The website operator does not use this information to identify you. However, the website operator reserves the right to subsequently check the server log files if there are concrete indications of illegal use.

### Cookies

This website uses "cookies" - small text files, without any personal data, that are stored on your computer or mobile device. Your browser accesses these files. We do not track your personal data through cookies.

You can adjust your browser settings to receive a message every time a cookie is installed on your computer or to prevent their installation altogether. Although rejection of cookies will not interfere with your ability to interact with most of this website, you will need to accept cookies if you choose to use areas of this website that might require registration or login, such as the forum. Certain functions and/or services, such as posting your messages at the forum, might be unavailable to you if you reject cookies altogether.

### Google Analytics

This website uses the "Google Analytics" service, which is provided by Google Inc. _(1600 Amphitheatre Parkway Mountain View, CA 94043, USA)_ for website usage analysis. The service uses cookies. The information collected by the cookies is usually sent to a Google server in the USA and stored there.

IP anonymisation is used on this website. The IP address of users within the member states of the EU and the European Economic Area will be reduced. This reduction eliminates the personal reference to your IP address. As part of the contract data agreement concluded between the website operators and Google Inc., Google uses the information collected to evaluate the use of the website and website activity and to provide services related to Internet use.

The information collected with visitor cookies and through the Google Analytics service is used to gain a better understanding of which sections of this website are most important to the users as well as identify possible navigation issues. Thus it increases the user-friendliness and security of this website.

You have the option of preventing the storage of cookies on your device by making the appropriate settings in your browser.

Furthermore, you can use a browser plug-in to prevent the information collected by cookies _(including your IP address)_ from being sent to Google Inc. and used by Google Inc. The following link leads you to the corresponding plugin: <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>

Here you will find further information on data use by Google Inc.: <https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245>

## Rights of the User: Information, Correction, and Deletion

Upon your request, you as a user will receive free information about what personal data about you has been stored. Unless your request conflicts with a legal obligation to store data _(e.g. data retention)_ , you have a right to have incorrect data corrected and your personal data blocked or deleted.

_May 14, 2018_
